Maalik McBurrows

Software Engineer Atlanta, GA | (404) 884-0788

https://maalik-mcburrows.github.io/portfolio-v2/ | https://github.com/maalik-mcburrows | https://www.linkedin.com/in/maalik-mcburrows-b363731a3/ | maalikmcburrows1@gmail.com

About Me

Junior software engineer with the capacity and desire to learn and adapt to new programming languages and technologies. Before I became a software engineer I attended college where I spent two years in an undergraduate degree program and completed my general studies coursework. I also worked part time in addition to my studies, mostly in the service industry where I was able to further develop my communication, teamwork, and leadership skills, while also learning several positions in the span of months and occasionally performing some managerial tasks when needed.

Software Development Skills

• JavaScript, Python, Linux, Node.js, React/Redux, Express, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, Web APIs, Git/GitHub, Bootstrap, Flexbox, Grid, AWS, HTML, CSS, Debugging

Education

Georgia Southern University | Statesboro, GA August 2017 – May 2018

Gwinnett Technical College | Lawrenceville, GA August 2018 - May 2019

• Intensive software engineering bootcamp with a fast paced learning environment centered around the overall development of foundational level programming concepts and languages including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, with an emphasis on cutting- edge frameworks like React/Redux, and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Software Development Portfolio

Front End | https://github.com/maalik-mcburrows/Front-End-Project Feb 2020

- Second project for the Digital Crafts bootcamp where we utilized front end skills learned in previous weeks of class to construct a basic website.
- This website allows you to research entertainment events and venues in your area using the Ticketmaster API and Google Maps API for geolocation.
 - Languages used include Javascript, HTML, and CSS.

Back End | https://github.com/maalik-mcburrows/Back-End-Project March 2020

- Part of a 3 person team where we built a website for viewing, reviewing, and creating routes for mountain climbers storing popular routes, user credentials, and various other pieces of information in our own database.
- Personal contributions to the project included building and maintaining the routes of the different pages, creating interactive buttons for the user to navigate the site, and creating new user and login authentication processes.
 - Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL

Capstone | https://instatracker.netlify.app/ April-May 2020

- The Insta-Tracker app was designed to show a plethora of up to date information regarding the novel COVID-19 global pandemic.
- The app includes: the latest YouTube video updates from the CDC's COVID-19 playlist, the latest tweets from the CDC's Twitter account , several news articles regarding the pandemic, as well as U.S. totals for positive tests, total deaths, from each state/territory.

Professional Work Experience

Chipotle | Crew Member | Alpharetta, GA June 2018 – December 2019

- Assist fellow crew members in providing an exceptional dining experience for guests through various tasks such as preparing, cooking, and serving food.
- During my time here I learned every position and taught these positions and their inner-workings to other coworkers.

UPS | Driver Helper | Roswell, GA December 2017 – January 2018

- Assist driver to distribute orders and packages during the holiday season, the busiest time of the year for the e-commerce industry.
- Utilized device that allowed user to input a driving route and displayed most efficient delivery route in order of location address succession.

Roswell Pediatric Dentistry and Orthodontics Call Center | Roswell, GA November 2016 – April 2017

• Receive incoming and distribute outgoing calls to patients in order to schedule/reschedule/cancel appointments, finalize transactions, and other miscellaneous inquiries required to ensure customer satisfaction.